

# Joshua Nguyen

# Software Developer Intern | CS Student



# **Summary**

I am a learner of all things software from inside and out. I have been a active programmer since the age of 15. Even since, I dive myself into a world of informations and algorithms that entice my passion to continue the pathway as a programmer. First programming language was Java, then it was C++. C++ thrives my enthusiasm with many IDE and SDK software such as game development and software in day to day basis needs. I specialized in game development such as Unity/ Unreal Engine 4 and .NET devlopment for desktop apps and sometimes websites. I am right now currently learning VR development so I can kickstart my career as maybe a future indie game developer. Even to this day, I am still learning each and every day to learn more about software implematation and how real world development works as time passes since learning my first code, "Hello World"!



### **Experience**

2017-09 -2017-12

### **Software Developer Intern**

White Code Labs

- Programming C# .NET Projects and Apps for clients' needed expectations
- Perform software testing in case of debugging and errors.
- Using the latest software tools such as Docker and Visual Studios 2016 to maintain containers to clients and compile unique software.
- Assist and self-reliant in performing tasks and learning new soft skills on the job.

2018-10 -2018-11

### Web Developer Intern

Fruition Technology Labs

- Build a home page website using the latest web technology such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Collaborate with other non-programmers and marketing team to get customers to attract to our website.

# **Education**

2016-01 -

### **University of Houston**

2018-12

Houston, Texas, Computer Science, 3.0 GPA

2019-01 - present

# **University of Houston Victoria at Katy Campus**

Katy, Texas, Computer Science, 3.0 GPA



# **Software and Projects**

Visual Studio (ASP.NET), Dev C++, and MonoDevelop



Unity3D(Game SDK), Blender, Unreal Engine 4(Game SDK), 3DS Maya/Max





#### Address

7431 Allen Pines

#### **Phone**

281-857-1351

#### E-mail

joshua@twinb0rnsoft.com

#### Date of birth

1995-05-11

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/ReckoningHero

#### WWW

http://www.twinb0rnsoft.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuangu yensoft1995/



C++, C#, Java, .NET Development (Application Development)



Jekyll , JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS (Web Development)



### **DirectX 2D Project: X Marks the Spot**

••••

Objective: Present a possible framework that can entice to a game environment without game editor. • Asserting and building the C++ framework from scratch using the latest DirectX 11 dependencies and files.

2D DirectX game initialing the user to obtain the goal up to 20 times

URL: https://github.com/ReckoningHero/X-Marks-the-Spot

### **Arduino Unity Project:**

Objective: Educate users to learn the basics of Arduino in a short span of time with Unity3D. • TEAM PROJECT: Credit for First person mechanism and Room scene(Physics, Tables, and player's movement)

URL: http://www.twinb0rnsoft.com/Portfolio/